{ "questions" :
  [
    {"question" : "What kind of method is 'new' in a = Array.new([1, 3, 2])",
     "answer" : "class",
     "info" : "When a method gets called on the class itself, as in the case of 'new', itâ€™s called a class method."},

    {"question" : "What kind of method is 'length' in arr.length (arr = [1,2,3])",
     "answer" : "instance",
     "info" : "A method called on an instance of a class is called an instance method."},

    {"question" : "Open text.txt in append only mode and set it to 'text'",
     "answer" : "text = File.open('text.txt', 'a')",
     "info" : "Starts at end of file if file exists; 'a+' read-write"},

    {"question" : "Read text = File.open('text.txt', 'r')",
     "answer" : "text.read",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Return to the beginning after text.read",
     "answer" : "text.rewind",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Read the first 10 characters of text",
     "answer" : "text.read(10)",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Write 'hi' to text = File.open('text.txt', 'w')",
     "answer" : "text.write('hi')",
     "info" : "text.close"},

    {"question" : "Append 'bye' to text = File.open('text.txt', 'a')",
     "answer" : "text.write('bye')",
     "info" : "text.close"},

    {"question" : "Create a block that adds two numbers and set it to the variable add",
     "answer" : "add = lambda {|a, b| return a + b }",
     "info" : "A block is code that you can store in a variable and run on demand."},

    {"question" : "Run the add block ( add = lambda {|a, b| return a + b } )",
     "answer" : "add.call(5, 6)",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Use a shortcut to create a block that adds two numbers and set it to 'add'",
     "answer" : "add = -> {|a, b| return a + b }" ,
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Find the superclass of Float",
     "answer" : "Float.superclass",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Turn 'cats and dogs' into an array",
     "answer" : "%w'cats and dogs'",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Use a range to select the first 3 elements of arr = %w'cats and dogs and mice'.",
     "answer" : "arr[0..2]" ,
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Use map and a block variable to downcase %w[A B C]",
     "answer" : "%w[A B C].map { |char| char.downcase }",
     "info" : ""},

    {"question" : "Use map and a symbol to downcase %w[A B C]",
     "answer" : "%w[A B C].map { &:downcase }",
     "info" : "https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1217088/what-does-mapname-mean-in-ruby"},

    {"question" : "END",
     "answer" : "END",
     "info" : "********* 6.json is next **********\n"}
  ]
}